ed.ac.uk 2011-06-08

# Website privacy policy | About our website

The University of Edinburgh (“ **the University** ”) is committed to preserving your privacy. Please read the following privacy policy to understand how we use and protect the information obtained from those visiting and using the University’s website www.ed.ac.uk (the “ **Site** ”).

By using the Site you consent to the collection/retention and use of your personal information in accordance with this policy.

## Information that we collect from you 

We collect information about you:

  * when you provide us with your personal details (such as your name, contact details, e-mail address etc) by registering with us or submitting an enquiry via the Site; 
  * when you respond to surveys which we ask you to complete for research purposes; and
  * from your usage of the Site and any other information you post on the site, e-mail or otherwise send to us.

## Use of your information

We use your information:

  * to enable us to supply you with the goods, services and information which you have requested; 
  * to ensure that content from the Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * to analyse the information we collect so that we can administer, support and improve and develop the Site;
  * to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;
  * to notify you about changes to our service.

We may contact you by post, telephone or fax as well as by e-mail and SMS. If you change your mind about being contacted in the future by any of these means then please let us know.

## Storage of your information

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

Any payment transactions will be encrypted. Some areas of the Site use third-party software facilities such as WorldPay. Please note that, data storage on WorldPay systems, and the communication between WorldPay and the worldwide banking networks, is regularly audited by the banking authorities to ensure a secure transaction environment. They also ensure that they stay up-to-date with the latest versions of any third-party code used, and continually review their own proprietary code.

## Disclosure of your information 

Authorised personnel within the University will be able to access the information you provide to us. We may also disclose your information to other third parties who act for us for the purposes set out in the policy or for purposes approved by you.

Please note that countries outside the European Economic Area do not always have the same strong data protection laws. However, we will always take steps to ensure that your information is used by third parties in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Unless required or permitted do so by law, we will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your consent.

## IP addresses and cookies

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type. This information is statistical data about users' browsing actions and patterns, does not identify any individual. It is used to inform improvements to the website, for system administration, and to report aggregate information to third parties.

For the same reasons, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. We use this information to track your movements through the Site, to find out how the Site is being used and to assess its usefulness. Personal information about you is not collected during the tracking process.

For more information on cookies please see:

We use a third party product “Google Analytics”, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”), to help us analyse how our Site is used. In doing so information about your use of our Site, including your IP address, may be transmitted to, and stored by, Google. This information will be subject to Google's Privacy Policy.

We may use persistent cookies if you have registered with us on-line. These cookies allow us to make the logging-in process easier and more secure. They will also be used to recognise you when you return to the Site. We may also use session cookies that will hold your data on our site until such time as you logout.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the Site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

## Security

We employ security measures to protect your information from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction or damage.

Please help us keep our records updated by informing us of any changes to your email address and other contact details.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may amend this policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes we will notify you by posting a prominent notice on the Site.

## Your rights

You have the right to ask for a copy of the information held by us in our records in return for which we charge a small fee.

The Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

## Contact us

If you have any queries concerning your personal information or any questions on our use of the information then please contact Records Management.

This article was published on Mar 18, 2011
